{
    "id": "2c6e7aaae5804681b0f499bd041fedb8",
    "title": "If Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If she ……………………….., we would be in trouble.",
            "description": "Was and were are both correct here however, were is more correct. In the second conditional, use a simple past tense in the if clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "finds out",
                "found out",
                "had found out"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "78198f8164a94d279c3fb24a3b353257"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………. guilty, you will pay the price.",
            "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "were",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "256dc574fe6a49efa8981def5b7ddf3a"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you eat too much, you ………………………… fat.",
            "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will get",
                "would get",
                "would have got"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "523700eb14e043faa4a367ed13e0e33f"
        },
        {
            "question": "If they started in the morning, they ………………………… here soon.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past tense in the if clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will be",
                "would be",
                "would have been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9784d0cc97b546b9b30f68b100cf648a"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she has a good job, why ………………………….. she seem to have enough money?",
            "description": "In the zero conditional, we use a simple present tense in both clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "doesn't",
                "didn't",
                "hadn't"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9a9ea0952fda41ed95bf95bd3c1b6e84"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you were at the party, you ………………………….. my fiancé.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past tense in the if clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "can meet",
                "will be able to meet",
                "could meet"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "68603b034f7f43d5ba648a761ad8c665"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she spoke English, she ………………………… a better job.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past tense in the if clause and would/could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "can get",
                "could get",
                "could have got"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3d91d8148b4d4ddd9961308563d3bc3e"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you lend me thousand dollars, I ………………………… a car.",
            "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "can buy",
                "could buy",
                "could have bought"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "392f3115203a4a3d8498109951aee261"
        },
        {
            "question": "If their intentions are honest, we ………………………………. by them.",
            "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "would stand",
                "will have stood",
                "will stand"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "32e56ec1d2db4417a683f9b79008aa44"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had known his motive, I ……………………………….. him.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will not support",
                "will not have supported",
                "would not have supported"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9d5fd761cf974ce5b798b8f311aeb9ed"
        },
        {
            "question": "If my grandmother ………………………. alive today, she would turn 95 next month.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past tense in the if clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "were",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0b248dcbdf3441a4abf13d66464e74f5"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ................................ enough, I could lead a better life.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past tense in the if clause and would/could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "earn",
                "earned",
                "earns"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ab40095fec404aea887ae3d78c509975"
        }
    ]
}